all right so you got your terminal
you're using on on your Mac you're using
a Mac terminal and you've got it you got
the pretty colors you've install the
groove box theme those are separate
videos and now you need to get the
missing package manager it's called Brew
it's pretty much standard at this point
Mac should probably just put it on the
system by default um and to do that you
have to go uh download it you have to go
get it from the internet and download it
and right now it's still a little clunky
you have to run it from a very specific
location but we're going to fix all of
that so this video is about getting Brew
on your system now I already did this so
I could test it but I'm going to go
ahead and go through the steps again so
if you were just doing it for the first
time you would come out
to uh you come out to your web browser
and you'd search for brew for
mac and you'd see home brew the missing
package manager uh you would go here and
cut and paste this into your
terminal uh let's actually
change to small so you can see
it and um then so again you're over here
you search for brew you went to brew. sh
and now you have
it
somebody somebody's blur
me are they doing a was a sticker is
either a sticker or a
blurp all right so um so here we go
let's go ahead and U paste it so you
paste and then
enter and then you type in your password
which you should you
know uh
okay and we wait for it to to enter now
it's already got it there but what I
want to S show you right here is make
sure you pay attention to this see how
it says opt home brew
bin right
here right there see where it says opt
home brew bin right there remember that
because you're going to need to type
that in and for now eventually you'll
just be able to type Brew but for right
now you'll need to type that one part in
so let's go ahead and put P
enter and it'll install the whole thing
it'll get the latest one Gite
clutch
um max yeah all right so so that goes it
installs it all uh it tells you the
commands you should run uh I just want
to warn you right now these commands
right here don't run them you don't need
these commands these commands are
unnecessary they are based on zshell
which we're immediately going to get rid
of and we're going to use bash if you
want to use zshell because somebody
convinces you zshell is better fine
there's a separate video about why we're
using bash which is a default shell on
all Linux systems uh except for Cali so
we're going to go with bash and that's
why it's for right now you just need to
remember uh that one by there so you can
cut and paste this let's just copy and
paste this right now let's scroll back
down and this will get us
hopefully um what we need okay so there
we go we can see we got the Brew command
and we're going to use Brew to install
t-o and the latest bash and a bunch of
other stuff in other videos so that's
the end for that video um you
know Brew if you have a if you have a
Mac this is just the way to go it's what
it's what you really need so take the
time to go understand that install brew
and then come back and we'll watch
another video you can do the rest with
me later